Texas Sheet Music collection, Inclusive: 1836-1979, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Texas Sheet Music collection
Inclusive: 1836-1979, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
258
The Texas Collection, 1923 -
2 OVZ boxes
The Texas Sheet Music collection is an artificial assortment of songs and sheet music related to the state of Texas. Many of these songs pertain to the Texas War of Independence, famous military leaders, Christmas in Texas, the state flower, the state song, the city of Waco, and life in the American Southwest.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
The Texas Sheet Music collection is an artificial collection created over time by The Texas Collection staff from many different sources. All of the songs herein relate back to the central theme of the collection: life in Texas.
Scope and Content
The Texas Sheet Music collection is an artificial collection created by The Texas Collection through various gifts and purchases. The contents range in chronology from the Texas Revolutionary period (1836) to 1979 with some undated pieces.
Series I. Compositions is the only series found in this collection. It is comprised of songs and sheet music pertaining to life in Texas. Some of the more prominent themes that recur throughout the materials include the Texas Revolution, the Mexican-American War, World War I, patriotism, Christmas in Texas, the state flower, the state song, the state flag, the city of Waco, the Cotton Palace, and life in the Southwest. The materials in this collection are in average condition.
Arrangement
Prior to this latest round of processing, the Texas Sheet Music collection was housed in acid-free folders and boxes. The materials were organized alphabetically by title with multiple songs in each folder. There were no song titles or inclusive dates initially, but much of the preservation work had already been completed.
This original order has been maintained with the addition of each song title and the date range of each folder now included. All the songs are arranged alphabetically in a single series, I. Compositions.
In September 2017, all the sheet music related specifically to Baylor University was transferred into a new artificial collection, the BU Records: Baylor Sheet Music collection.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 258. Acquired 1980-05-14
Related Resources
Items in related collections
BU Records: Baylor Sheet Music collection, Inclusive: 1891-1941, undated
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Texas Cotton Palace (Waco, Tex.) -- Songs and music.
Places
Texas -- History -- Revolution, 1835-1836 -- Songs and music.; Texas -- Songs and music.; Waco (Tex.) -- Songs and music.
Subjects
Christmas music -- Texas -- Specimens.; Emblems, State -- Texas -- Songs and music.; Mexican War, 1846-1848 -- Songs and music.; Military music -- Texas -- Specimens.; Patriotic music -- Texas -- Specimens.; World War, 1914-1918 -- Songs and music.
- Compositions, 1836-1979, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  Series I. Compositions, the only series in the Texas Sheet Music collection, consists of songs and scores related to the state of Texas. The themes represented in this collection are quite diverse with particular emphasis on the Texas War for Independence, the Mexican-American War, Christmas in Texas, the city of Waco, patriotism, and life in the American Southwest. The contents of this series are arranged alphabetically by title and are in average condition.
  - "Across the Alley from the Alamo," "Air Mestizia," "The Alamo," "Are You From Texas Too," and "Armadillo Polka", 1933-1972 (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - "The Ballad of Davy Crockett," "The Battle of Buena Vista," "Battleship Texas March," "Beautiful Fredericksburg," "Beautiful Texas," and "Beat Me Daddy Eight to the Bar", 1847-1979 (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - "Blackbird, Keep Singing," "Blue Bonnet, The Flower of the Lone Star State," "The Blue Bonnet, Flower of Texas," "Blue Bonnet, Texas Flavored Flower," "Blue Bonnet Time," and "Blue Bonnets in Texas", 1915-1939, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - "Bonny Blue Bonnet," "A Boy from Texas-A Girl from Tennessee," "The Brazos Boat Glee," "Brazos Boat Song," and "By the Silver Rio Grande", 1838-1947, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - "Come On Texas," "Corpus Christi, Texas on the Bay," and "Cotton Palace March", 1910-1936, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - "Deep in the Heart of Texas," "Dripping Springs," "Du Bist Wie Eine Blume," and "Evergreen Schottisch", 1890-1941, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - "Fiesta," "The Flag of Texas," "Flag Song of Texas," "The Flag with the Single Star," "Flower of Texas," and "For God and Texas", 1836-1956 (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - "General Taylor's Encampment Quick Step," "Getting Rich in Texas," "Glorious Texas," "Gonna Build a Big Fence Around Texas," "Good Morning Texas," and "Grand Old Friendly Texas", 1845-1944 (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - "Hail Texas," "Happiest Party in All the Land," "Happy Birthday, U.S.A.," "Help Yourself," "Her Cowboy Lover," and "Houston by the Sea", 1911-1976 (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - "I'd Be Happy With You in a Cotton Palace," "I'd Like to Be in Texas for the Round Up in the Spring," "I'm Coming Back to You My Texas," "I'm Going Back to Texas and the Silvery Rio Grande," "If Only I Hadn't Believed in You," "In the Land of the Buffalo," and "In the Shadow of the Sacred Alamo", 1902-1935, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 10)
  - "The Jetties March-Two Step," "Lone Star of Texas," and "Lover's Leap", 1898-1944, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 11)
  - "Macbeth," "Magnolia Triumphal," "Maybe He's Your Boy in Khaki, Maybe He's Your Boy in Blue," and "Merry Texas Christmas, You All", 1942-1951, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 12)
  - "My Dear Old Texas Home," "My Galveston Gal," "My Little Wahco Maid," "My Old, Old Texas Home," "My Texas", "My Texas Blue Bonnet," and "My Texas Home", 1906-1958 (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 13)
  - "The New Texas Dixie," "The Night Before Christmas in Texas," and "Nuts and Raisins", 1919-1956 (Box 2 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - "On the Old Spanish Trail," "One Hundred Years Ago," "Out in My Garden," "Out Ole Santa Rosa Way," and "Pistol Packin' Mama", 1943-1952, undated (Box 2 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - "The Ranger's Song," "Remember the Alamo," "Roosevelt's March Through Texas," and "Rose of the Rio Grande", 1908-1926, undated (Box 2 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - "Sam Houston," "San Antonio Rose," "San Antonio Song," and "Seguin: A Centennial Song", 1907-1945 (Box 2 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - "Soldier, Statesman, Knightly, Gentleman," "Some Sunday Morning," "Sons of Texas," "South of the Border," "Spirit of the Alamo," "Spirit of Waco High," "Sul Ross Grand March," and "Sunny Texas", 1898-1955 (Box 2 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - "Take Me Back to Amarillo," "Take Me Back to My Saddle," "Tejas," and "Texanita", 1926-1952, undated (Box 2 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - "Texas and Brazo's Navigation Waltz," "Texas and Her Flag," "Texas Blue Bonnet Song," "The Texas Centennial Waltz," "The Texas Cotton Palace March and Two-Step," "Texas Federation March," and "Texas I Love You", 1909-1956 (Box 2 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - "The Texas Maiden March," "Texas, My Texas," and "Texas Nightingale Waltz", 1896-1918 (Box 2 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - "Texas, Our Texas", 1925-1954 (Box 2 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - "A Texas Overture," "Texas Polka," "The Texas Polka," and "Texas, Pride of the South", 1909-1947, undated (Box 2 OVZ, Folder 10)
  - "Texas Quick Step," "Texas Shadows," "Texas, A Patriotic Song," "Texas Song," "The Texas Star," "Texas Star March," and "Texas State Song", 1841-1930, undated (Box 2 OVZ, Folder 11)
  - "Texas the Great," "Texas Triumphant," and "Texas Where the Mockin' Bird is Singin' ", 1898-1925 (Box 2 OVZ, Folder 12)
  - "The Texian Grand March," "Texian Hymn of Liberty," "That's Texas," "There Will Always Be a Texas," and "A Touch of Texas", 1836-1956 (Box 2 OVZ, Folder 13)
  - "Under a Texas Moon," "The Vera Cruz Grand March," "Victoria Sesquicentennial March Two-Step," and "Vote for Grover Cleveland", 1847-1929 (Box 2 OVZ, Folder 14)
  - "Waters of the Old Rio Grande," "We Will Boost You, Texas," "What the Little Blue Star Means to Me," "When It's Christmas in Texas," "When the Bloom is on the Sage," "Will You Come to the Bower," "Without You Darling," and "The World War Blues", 1918-1958, undated (Box 2 OVZ, Folder 15)
  - "The Yellow Rose of Texas", 1858-1955, undated (Box 2 OVZ, Folder 16)